<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>servicemesh on Amazon EKS Workshop</title><link>/tags/servicemesh/</link><description>Recent content in servicemesh on Amazon EKS Workshop</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 16:32:30 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/servicemesh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Service Mesh with Istio</title><link>/advanced/310_servicemesh_with_istio/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 16:32:30 +0900</pubDate><guid>/advanced/310_servicemesh_with_istio/</guid><description>Service Mesh With Istio A service mesh is a dedicated infrastructure layer for handling service-to-service communication. It’s responsible for the reliable delivery of requests through the complex topology of services that comprise a modern, cloud native application.
Service mesh solutions have two distinct components that behave somewhat differently: 1) a data plane, and 2) a control plane. The following diagram illustrates the basic architecture.
The data planeis composed of a set of intelligent proxies (Envoy) deployed as sidecars.</description></item><item><title>Service Mesh with App Mesh</title><link>/advanced/320_servicemesh_with_appmesh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 08:30:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>/advanced/320_servicemesh_with_appmesh/</guid><description>At re:invent 2018, we announced AWS App Mesh, a service mesh that provides application-level networking to make it easy for your services to communicate with each other across multiple types of compute infrastructure. App Mesh standardizes how your services communicate, giving you end-to-end visibility and ensuring high-availability for your applications.
Service meshes like AWS App Mesh help you to run and monitor HTTP and TCP services at scale. Whether your application consists of AWS Fargate, Amazon EC2, Amazon ECS, Amazon Kubernetes Service, or Kubernetes clusters or instances, App Mesh provides consistent routing and traffic monitoring functionality, giving you insight into problems and the ability to re-route traffic after failures or code changes.</description></item></channel></rss>