<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>intermediate on Amazon EKS Workshop</title><link>/tags/intermediate/</link><description>Recent content in intermediate on Amazon EKS Workshop</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 16:32:30 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/intermediate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Intermediate</title><link>/intermediate/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>/intermediate/</guid><description>Intermediate</description></item><item><title>IAM Roles for Service Accounts</title><link>/beginner/110_irsa/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 16:32:30 +0900</pubDate><guid>/beginner/110_irsa/</guid><description>Fine-Grained IAM Roles for Service Accounts In Kubernetes version 1.12, support was added for a new ProjectedServiceAccountToken feature, which is an OIDC JSON web token that also contains the service account identity, and supports a configurable audience.
Amazon EKS now hosts a public OIDC discovery endpoint per cluster containing the signing keys for the ProjectedServiceAccountToken JSON web tokens so external systems, like IAM, can validate and accept the Kubernetes-issued OIDC tokens.</description></item><item><title>Securing Your Cluster with Network Policies</title><link>/beginner/120_network-policies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Nov 2018 08:30:11 -0700</pubDate><guid>/beginner/120_network-policies/</guid><description>Securing your cluster with network policies In this chapter, we are going to use two tools to secure our cluster by using network policies and then integrating our cluster&amp;rsquo;s network policies with EKS security groups.
First we will use Project Calico to enforce Kubernetes network policies in our cluster, protecting our various microservices.
After that, we will use Tigera&amp;rsquo;s Secure Cloud Edition to integrate the Kubernetes network policies with Amazon&amp;rsquo;s VPC security groups.</description></item><item><title>Exposing a Service</title><link>/beginner/130_exposing-service/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>/beginner/130_exposing-service/</guid><description>Exposing a Service Introduction In this Chapter, we will review how to configure a Service, Deployment or Pod to be exposed outside our cluster. We will also review the different ways to do so.</description></item><item><title>Assigning Pods to Nodes</title><link>/beginner/140_assigning_pods/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 00:00:00 -0300</pubDate><guid>/beginner/140_assigning_pods/</guid><description>Assigning Pods to Nodes Introduction In this Chapter, we will review how the strategy of assigning Pods works, alternatives and recommended approaches.
You can constrain a pod to only be able to run on particular nodes or to prefer to run on particular nodes.
Generally such constraints are unnecessary, as the scheduler will automatically do a reasonable placement (e.g. spread your pods across nodes, not place the pod on a node with insufficient free resources, etc.</description></item><item><title>Advanced VPC Networking with EKS</title><link>/beginner/160_advanced-networking/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2019 16:47:38 -0500</pubDate><guid>/beginner/160_advanced-networking/</guid><description>Advanced VPC Networking with EKS In this Chapter, we will review some of the advanced VPC networking features with EKS.</description></item></channel></rss>